ShuHei Ito

hahadev@proton.me

https://www.linkedin.com/in/shuhei-ito-71511628b/

Skills Summary

- Go / DevOps/ Amazon Web Services / Blockchain / NFT / Smart Contract / Rust
- JavaScript / TypeScript / Node / React / React Native / Vue / Angular / Next / Nest
- MySQL / PostgreSQL / MongoDB
- AppSync, GraphQL, S3, EC2, REST API Development, Docker, Microservices Architecture, Version control with Git, Issue tracking (Jira, Trello)
- CI/CD with Bitbucketx
- Unit & Integration Testing with Enzyme, Jest, etc.

I am a full-stack engineer with 8 years of experience in multiple languages and frame works. My passion is taking on complex business challenges and designing full-stack solutions.

I have experience developing web applications using Go, Rust, Blockchain, React, Vue, Laravel/Express, Swift and Python/Django. Additionally, I have experience in Go/Echo/Gin and have deployed over 10 new projects using React, Laravel, and Go.

Thuoughout my career, I've collebrated with startups across various industries, including Healthcare, Booking, Blockchain, Real Estate, FinTech, Music, E-commerce, more.

Are you searching for a dedicated full-stack developer who is eager to learn and become an integral part of your team? Let's have a conversation!

Education

The University of Tokyo

As a Bachelor's degree holder in Computer Science and law I feel confident and have a lot of fun solving logical and computational problems such as Algorithm & Programming and Computer Science.

Experience

Fixer company, Inc - Contract

Senior Blockchain / Golang Engineer
Oct 2022-Oct 2023 (10 mos)
Darlington, Maryland, United States - remote

Technologies: Go, Python, Ethereum(Smart Contracts), Rust(Programming Language), DevOps, Amazon Web Services, Microservices, React, React, Redux, ...

- Manage common Goroutine and channel patterns.
- Work on Go programming language, paradigms, constructs, and idioms.

Senior Blockchain / Golang Engineer Aug 2020 – Oct 2022 (2yrs 3mos) Darlington, Maryland, United States - remote

Technologies: Go, Blockchain, React, React Native, Node.js, Express.js, Redux, Redux-saga, Postman, Trello, Figma

- Lead the team in development
- Contributed to work on Blockchain Technologies via Golang, JavaScript(React, React Native)
- Led the development of a hybrid app for web, mobile and voice devices as a reading companion for print media called Booke.
- Managed a team of two software developers and one designer and ensured their performance met the desired standards.
- Developed a responsive website and application using React.
- Implemented efficient and maintainable code by refactoring the inner codebase.
- Tracked and resolved issues and managed project tickets via Trello to maintain transparency across theteam.
- Successfully launched Booke across Silicon Valley's libraries, colleges, and universities, including San Francisco University and Stanford University.

Golang / Rust Developer
Jul 2018 - Jul 2020 (2 yrs 1mo)
Darlington, Maryland, United States - remote

Technologies: Go, Node.js, Angular, PostgreSQL, Swift, Redis, AWS S3, Amazon Cognito, Microsoft Azure

- Developed maintenance processes for Pressly, a content marketing platform that helped businesses curate and distribute content to their target audiences.
- Defined product requirements and collaborated with cross-functional teams to develop the platform, which was built using a combination of technologies, including Go, Angular, and MongoDB.
- Developed the go-to-market strategy, including pricing, positioning, and messaging, and oversaw the marketing and sales efforts to promote the platform. including Cisco, Salesforce, and Deloitte, and ensured their needs were met through regular communication and product updates.
- Successfully grew the platform's user base to over 1,000 customers, resulting in a multi-million dollar annual revenue stream.

Full-stack Developer
May 2017 - Jun 2018 (1yrs 2mos)
Butler, Pennsylvania, United States - remote

Technologies: Go(Programming Language), JavaScript, TypeScript, Vue, AWS, MySQL, Node.js, Gin, BackEnd Web Development, React.js, PostgreSQL

- Involved in upgrading the existing applications as well as building 10 web applications.
- Experience implementing both frontend and backend.
- Delivered user-friendly, pixel-perfect UI pages with UI designed in Figma and Sketch.
- Built five MVPs from start to finish focusing on good user experience and product scalability.
- Built the microservices and serverless architecture for several applications with AWS.

- Collaborated with the product manager on UX issues on the frontend using JavaScript, jQuery, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, and Less.
- Provided APIs and libraries to assist other developers.

Awards and Acknowledgements

Golden Award May the 4th Challenge

Codility cert EE6B4E-893AR2QZHDA7TAQV